## Fábio Ferreira

#### Fullstack Developer

#### Summary

Fullstack Developer with over 4 years of professional experience and 6+ years of coding expertise, specializing in frontend development and UI/UX design. With a foundation in design and a career in cybersecurity, I deliver web solutions that combine aesthetics, functionality, and resilience.

For a more detailed view of my work, technologies used and other details, visit my portfolio at https://fabiof.dev

#### **Technical Skills**

- Frontend: Typescript, React, NextJS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Storybook, MaterialUI
- Backend: NodeJS, ExpressJS, PHP, MySQL, Firebase
- Other Tools: Figma, Git, GitLab, Github, Docker, Vitest, Jira, SonarQube, Windows, Linux

#### Work Experience

#### Fullstack Developer & UX/UI Designer | Layer8 - Cybersecurity Company

Aug 2022 - Present

- Lead developer for the company's component library, reducing development time by 50% through reusable, secure
  and responsive components.
- Leading the development of a cloud management platform to centralize the company's services, with features such as user and service management.
- Contributed significantly to redesigning and restructuring legacy projects to align with the new design guidelines and component library, ensuring 100% design consistency across projects.
- Consulted on security best practices for web applications, minimizing vulnerabilities and improving system reliability.

#### Fullstack Developer & UX/UI Designer | Freelancer

Dez 2021 - Present

- Designed and developed websites focusing on responsive design and performance optimization creating a stronger online presence for clients.
- Produced diverse creative solutions, including graphic design and multimedia projects, delivering 100% client satisfaction through cohesive and polished results.

#### Frontend Developer | Gestix - Invoice Company

Jan 2021 - Nov 2021

- Rebuilt and redesigned the company's main website, improving performance and user experience by 20%.
- Developed a customizable, UI/UX-friendly website template for clients, Increasing customer satisfaction by 35%.
- Redesigned the back-office interface to improve usability and user experience.

# Fábio Ferreira

### Fullstack Developer

Santarém, Portugal       ♣ +351 927 671 290       ➡ me@fabiof.dev       ♠ fabiof.dev         In linkedin.com/in/fabio-m-ferreira       ♠ github.com/fabio-m-ferreira	
Education	
Google UX Design Professional Certificate   Corsera	2023
Grade: average of 92.19% on all 7 courses	
Certificate: Corsera Certificate Link	
Developing Secure Software (LFD121)   Linux Foundation	2023
Certificate: <u>Linux Foundation Certificate Link</u>	
Web Development   ETIC	2019 - 2020
• Grade 18/20	
Multimedia Technician - High School   Multimedia Technician - High School	2016 - 2019

• Grade: 16/20